<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-08T14:47:45-05:00</updated><id>https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Impulsive Updates</title><subtitle>This is an informative collection of what I deem important about selective topics.</subtitle><author><name>Puls3</name></author><entry><title type="html">What’s With Paldera</title><link href="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/paldera/whats-with-paldera/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What's With Paldera" /><published>2020-01-26T22:46:32-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-26T22:46:32-05:00</updated><id>https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/paldera/whats-with-paldera</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/paldera/whats-with-paldera/">&lt;p&gt;So recently I’ve been browsing the r/PBBG subreddit,
and I came across a treasure trove of drama from a game that hasn’t even released yet.
I’ve decided to write up a report about my findings for everyone to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;; The things I write here are my own thoughts and words and do not reflect the opinions or views of Pendoria or Ethereal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side Note&lt;/strong&gt;; I’ve decided to keep this post off of r/PBBG, as I’d like to not get the disapproving glare from FoohonPie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow Up Edit&lt;/strong&gt;; Due to the following line from FoohonPie - I’ve decided to post it on r/PBBG too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;No disapproving glares here. Discussion is totally welcome, we just had to lock the existing threads temporarily due to some bickering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much love to FoohonPie, moving on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-it&quot;&gt;So what is it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic of our post today is Paldera.
Hmm, Paldera… that name sounds familiar but I can’t quite put my finger on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paldera is an unreleased PBBG made by Reddit user publishcoffee that claims to be the “most progressive and hi-tech web based game ever made”.
But today we aren’t going to talk about the game, because we don’t know much about that just yet, instead we are going to talk about what’s going with Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So from what I’ve been able to dig up the creator and developer of Paldera has decided to enforce strict rules regarding messaging about the game outside of the official channels.
An example of this is the promised banning of the user that created the unofficial Paldera subreddit, which was originally created due to strict moderation on the official Paldera subreddit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-to-the-point&quot;&gt;Get to the point!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response to these actions, people began to question &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; he feels he needs to do this,
he simply replied to multiple inquiries that he’s only enforcing the rules for his own game and will not allow anyone to break them without punishment.
He seems to believe that in doing so he will be able to protect his players somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the response provided by publishcoffee;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m not interested in tightly curating content and messaging about my game,
what I am interested in doing is making sure the rules are enforced and that there aren’t the problems I’ve already stated I’m trying to prevent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s all well and good that he’s enforcing the rules for his game,
that’s something I like to see in game administrators - I feel the rules he’s attempting to enforce are far to harsh.
They require him to prevent even talking about the game on unofficial channels, which leads me to question why he’s okay with the r/PBBG subreddit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When accused of micromanaging he proceeded to say this;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m simply managing, and I feel that people are making it seem like I’m reaching when I’m actually just enforcing my own rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response to both statements Reddit user Vsrap claimed the following;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Actually, you are micromanaging.
You’ve stated that people won’t be allowed to have Discord servers for their own guild because you want to control what is said regarding your game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I read that correctly? New section!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;private-discords-are-ban-worthy&quot;&gt;Private Discord’s are ban worthy?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the former comments, publishcoffee reinforced Vsrap’s statement by saying;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;People can chat in-game for their own guilds and what not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless he plans to implement voice chat with the same quality as a million dollar corporation like Hammer and Chisel did for Discord,
I don’t see how his in-game chat could be a good alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s even more alarming is the following question, how does he plan to enforce this rule?
The only thing that comes to mind is banning anyone that posts a Discord invite link within &lt;strong&gt;private&lt;/strong&gt; guild chats.
And what does he plan to do when the major guilds from other games that already have Discords attempt to branch into Paldera?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;he-didnt-clearly-state-that-though&quot;&gt;He didn’t clearly state that though!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having written this post, publishcoffee (or Dustin as he’s being called by some, which is also his Discord username) decided to post a clarification of his policy.
Some users took this as a sign that maybe his policy does allow Discord servers, however the following quotes from a conversation between Vsrap and publishcoffee would prove otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Vsrap’s initial query;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Any comment on banning players who want a guild Discord server?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response publishcoffee offered a vague response as opposed to a clear, direct statement in which Vsrap seemed to be searching for.
Which given how confusing many of these answers have been, I understand his frustration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As I’ve stated, I don’t condone unofficial communities. Players who go against the policies of Paldera will be banned. This question has already been answered multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a little more talking publishcoffee replied the following;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I was trying to answer it in a way that was obvious. But I guess it didn’t come out that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end it seems this is the most clear of an answer we will be able to get,
so we now know 100% that uuunofficial Paldera guild Discords will result in &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; the creator getting banned.
He has not yet stated if the participants of these unofficial communities will be punished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-now&quot;&gt;So What Now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally I don’t know what to make of this game so far, you can all form your own opinions.
Just know that I’ll be including more information related to this soon (via editing this post),
however I’m too tired of this to continue at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not good at writing posts like this, it was less information and more quoting left and right.
Which personally I find difficult to write about, however I’ll do my best to get you all as much relevant information as I can find.
Which includes the following Reddit post where I got the majority of my information. The subreddit’s moderation has seen fit to lock the comment section, and for good reason as there’s been a lot of drama within it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is my mentioned source on the r/PBBG subreddit;
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/PBBG/comments/eu0j48/welcome_to_the_paldera_unofficial_subreddit/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/PBBG/comments/eu0j48/welcome_to_the_paldera_unofficial_subreddit/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the same link, but for old Reddit scrubs;
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/PBBG/comments/eu0j48/welcome_to_the_paldera_unofficial_subreddit/&quot;&gt;https://old.reddit.com/r/PBBG/comments/eu0j48/welcome_to_the_paldera_unofficial_subreddit/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-it&quot;&gt;That’s It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, that’s it for this post.
I’m going to continue to write up more, so if you enjoyed it then be sure to read the next one!
If you disliked it tell then me why down in the comments and I’ll consider your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I’m not gaining anything from this post,
so be sure to share it with your friends if you would like to reward me somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series of posts is archived at the link below if you missed any.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&quot;&gt;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Puls3</name></author><category term="Paldera" /><summary type="html">So recently I’ve been browsing the r/PBBG subreddit, and I came across a treasure trove of drama from a game that hasn’t even released yet. I’ve decided to write up a report about my findings for everyone to read.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Year &amp;amp; New Games</title><link href="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/deals/new-year-new-games/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Year &amp; New Games" /><published>2020-01-01T02:34:27-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T02:34:27-05:00</updated><id>https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/deals/new-year-new-games</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/deals/new-year-new-games/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;steep-is-free&quot;&gt;Steep Is Free!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago I was telling players to download UPlay just to get Steep for free,
well now another company has decided to provide this game free of charge.
If you didn’t guess from how generous they’ve been recently, it’s Epic Games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve played quite a bit of Steep myself and can personally recommend it as a great game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until January 9th of 2020 (it feels weird saying 2020) it will be free on Epic Games;
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/product/steep/home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/product/steep/home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;darksiders&quot;&gt;Darksiders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a game series I’ve never heard of,
but due to Epic Games deciding Steep wasn’t enough they’re also offering Darksiders and Darksiders II for free!
If this doesn’t get everyone reading to sign up on Epic Games then I don’t know what will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s links to the games;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/product/darksiders/home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Darksiders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/product/darksiders2/home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Darksiders II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;want-more&quot;&gt;Want More?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not entirely sure if these ones are always free (probably), but here’s two interesting games I found on GOG.
They both look pretty decent - and you can never have too many games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s links to the games;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gog.com/game/flight_of_the_amazon_queen&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Flight of the Amazon Queen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gog.com/game/cayne&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cayne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-it&quot;&gt;That’s It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, that’s it for this post.
I’m going to continue to write up more, so if you enjoyed it then be sure to read the next one!
If you disliked it tell then me why down in the comments and I’ll consider your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I’m not gaining anything from this post,
so be sure to share it with your friends if you would like to reward me somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series of posts is archived at the link below if you missed any.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&quot;&gt;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Puls3</name></author><category term="Deals" /><summary type="html">Steep Is Free!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Some Epic Deals</title><link href="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/deals/epic-deal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some Epic Deals" /><published>2019-12-22T00:30:36-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-22T00:30:36-05:00</updated><id>https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/deals/epic-deal</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/deals/epic-deal/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-game--10-coupon&quot;&gt;Free Game &amp;amp; $10 Coupon!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual Epic Games released their free game, there’s no real reason not to go pick it up.
In fact it seems there’s even more of a reason than usual, as this time not only do you get the game, you also receive a $10 coupon!
As usual there are limitations to using it, but either way the addition of it is a nice touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the limitations;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The $10 Epic Coupon can only be used on games already released on the Epic Games Store and priced at $14.99 or more after sale discounts have been applied.
This coupon cannot be used on pre-purchases or any non-game purchase such as add-ons
(like DLC or season passes) or in-game purchases (such as in-game currency,
like Vbucks in Fortnite, or upgrades like Save the World mode).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little thank you to my friend Ricardo for mentioning the limitations, if he hadn’t I would’ve forgotten to mention them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-game-a-day-makes-your-life-fade-away&quot;&gt;A Game A Day Makes Your Life Fade Away!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still on about Epic Games…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the holiday sale they have decided to release a game every single day during the “12 Days of Free Games”,
so for now you’re going to have to checkup on them a lot more than usual. The free game mentioned above is apart of this generously generous event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the link;
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/free-games&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/free-games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;portal--portal-2&quot;&gt;Portal &amp;amp; Portal 2!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I was suprised to see this earlier,
but I couldn’t help but notice that both Portal and Portal 2 are on sale for a dollar on Steam.
This lowers the Portal bundle down to a whopping $2!
Even if you’re not a Portal fan if you don’t already own these games you really should consider picking them up today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a link to the Portal Bundle;
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/bundle/234/Portal_Bundle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://store.steampowered.com/bundle/234/Portal_Bundle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-it&quot;&gt;That’s It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, that’s it for this post.
I’m going to continue to write up more, so if you enjoyed it then be sure to read the next one!
If you disliked it tell then me why down in the comments and I’ll consider your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I’m not gaining anything from this post,
so be sure to share it with your friends if you would like to reward me somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series of posts is archived at the link below if you missed any.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&quot;&gt;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Puls3</name></author><category term="Deals" /><summary type="html">Free Game &amp;amp; $10 Coupon!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What’s With DSRPG</title><link href="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/dsrpg/dsrpg-warning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What's With DSRPG" /><published>2019-12-21T05:46:32-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-21T05:46:32-05:00</updated><id>https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/dsrpg/dsrpg-warning</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/dsrpg/dsrpg-warning/">&lt;p&gt;First of all I understand that multiple posts were already made on this subject,
however I wanted to do my best to include all of the relevant information related to this disaster in one post.
Most of what I’ve had to rely on while gathering this information was private Discord servers,
private messages, rumors, and the brief posts on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-happened&quot;&gt;What happened?!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days ago someone manipulated DSRPG by uploading code into the image upload section, this gave the attackers control over the game.
Following this was a ton of chaos, and then what seemed to be order restored not long after.
It didn’t take long before users began to realize that the attackers had access to the entire database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meaning passwords as well…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-surely-theyre-encrypted&quot;&gt;But surely they’re encrypted?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The administration of Dragon Swords has assured us that passwords are indeed encrypted and that there is nothing to worry about,
however the original code writer (draven714 on Reddit) informed us that they are hashed via md5.
Any developer worth his salt would tell you md5 is no longer considered secure and might as well be plain text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quote directly from draven714;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;md5, no salt. So, please, change your passwords everywhere if you used the same password in DS on other sites!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To further reinforce this I have a quote from Vysn the owner of Avabur;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I cannot confirm, but there are rumors that DSRPG’s
(it’s a different PBBG - if you don’t know what it is or never played it, you have nothing to worry about) database was compromised.
If you made an account there and used the same password as you use here, consider changing your password here :shrug:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While he does say he cannot confirm,
the fact that a game owner thinks the issue is dire enough to warrant a notice should be enough, but all of this was before what happened next…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-happened-next&quot;&gt;What Happened Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a day after all of the chaos I was informed via reliable members of the community that dsrpg accounts are being taken over by the same person / people that were responsible for the earlier issues with dsrpg, 
reputable guild owner euphone (pickupeuphone on Reddit) has claimed that his accounts was logged into and used to delete his guild.
Additionally a few users here and there have also claimed to not be able to login anymore due to their passwords being changed without their knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quote directly from euphone;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I can personally confirm that my account was stolen while I was asleep,
the culprit was impersonating me on main chat,
deleted the guild I had leadership of, and that I can no longer log in.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;At this point, I am just waiting for HM to process the refund.
Others that bought in have said that they have already received theirs over the last couple of days,
so at least he is getting around to doing the right thing in that regard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-wait-theres-more&quot;&gt;But Wait! There’s More!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a few hours after I released this post there was yet another development,
and following with my original idea of putting all of the information in one place I’m going to edit it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PotentiallyVital, a vital part of DSRPG’s development team has left due to what we can assume is all of the chaos,
from what we know he was DSRPG’s primary developer and was going to be responsible for the upcoming rewrite.
Dragon Swords’ future is beginning to look even more bleak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-now&quot;&gt;So What Now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally I would urge all users to ensure that they change their password anywhere that they used the same (or similar) password as they did on dsrpg.
And if you want to keep your account on DS then change that one to a &lt;strong&gt;different&lt;/strong&gt; password, unless you want a hacker to impersonate you in main chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also to anyone that donated money to Dragon Swords I’ve heard second hand that they will accept charge-backs instantly,
though I don’t know how reliable that information is and won’t condone doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-it&quot;&gt;That’s It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, that’s it for this post.
I’m going to continue to write up more, so if you enjoyed it then be sure to read the next one!
If you disliked it tell then me why down in the comments and I’ll consider your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I’m not gaining anything from this post,
so be sure to share it with your friends if you would like to reward me somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post was also released on Reddit.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/PBBG/comments/eee8eh/whats_with_dsrpg/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reddit Version Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series of posts is archived at the link below if you missed any.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&quot;&gt;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Puls3</name></author><category term="DSRPG" /><summary type="html">First of all I understand that multiple posts were already made on this subject, however I wanted to do my best to include all of the relevant information related to this disaster in one post. Most of what I’ve had to rely on while gathering this information was private Discord servers, private messages, rumors, and the brief posts on the matter.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">December 5th Patch Notes</title><link href="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/december-5th-patch-details/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="December 5th Patch Notes" /><published>2019-12-05T05:46:32-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-05T05:46:32-05:00</updated><id>https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/december-5th--patch-details</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/december-5th-patch-details/">&lt;p&gt;It’s been 12 days since Pendoria pushed its latest update and we’ve been hard at work,
about an hour ago the server went down for a quick patch.
Here’s a post detailing what it included,
along with a few notes that might interest players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rhodium&quot;&gt;Rhodium&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve fixed a decent amount of bugs recently,
including one which caused all quintuple purchased with rhodium to reward twice the amount that it should.
This bug has been around for over a month and was just recently discovered,
on the upside this means that for over a month Pendoria has been matching all double purchases for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gifts&quot;&gt;Gifts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that there is now a new player requested feature; gifts! Gifting works almost exactly like wires, pardon the command is /gift and it does not inform the reciever of whom it was that sent the gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/gift user amount type&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small note that people have raised some concerns about spamming, we would like to state that we will not tolerate gifting with the intention of annoying the player whom is receiving the gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add to that, here’s an official statement from Admin Silent;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A small note that if anyone is receiving spam gifts, please report it to staff and the player will be dealt with accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wiring-cogs&quot;&gt;Wiring Cogs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of wires, you can now wire golden cogs, all of the following will work;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/wire user amount cog&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/wire user amount cogs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/wire user amount gc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No more cog buy orders for 1 each, unless you’re a serious low baller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;save-your-ingots&quot;&gt;Save Your Ingots&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have enough ingots to last you a week and through the event, then don’t use them!
In a week on December 13th the Scrapmas event will start, which is a perfect time to use your ingots - so be sure to save them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-it&quot;&gt;That’s It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, that’s it for this post.
I’m going to continue to write up more, so if you enjoyed it then be sure to read the next one!
If you disliked it tell then me why down in the comments and I’ll consider your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series of posts is archived at the link below if you missed any.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&quot;&gt;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-pendoria-if-you-havent&quot;&gt;Join Pendoria If You Haven’t!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t joined it’s never too late to start playing!
Below I have a referral link that helps me out on the game if you click it and sign up,
so please click that link, however if you don’t want to you can always click the other link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t care, click the first one, it doesn’t hurt you at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please Click Me; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pendoria.net/?ref=334&quot;&gt;https://pendoria.net/?ref=334&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Make Me Sad; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pendoria.net/&quot;&gt;https://pendoria.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Puls3</name></author><category term="Pendoria" /><summary type="html">It’s been 12 days since Pendoria pushed its latest update and we’ve been hard at work, about an hour ago the server went down for a quick patch. Here’s a post detailing what it included, along with a few notes that might interest players.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Timely Report</title><link href="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/so-whats-up/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Timely Report" /><published>2019-11-14T06:46:32-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-14T06:46:32-05:00</updated><id>https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/so-whats-up</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/so-whats-up/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;15-grand-for-charity&quot;&gt;1.5 Grand For Charity!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breast Cancer Awareness month ended a decent bit ago,
and as I mentioned in my last post, 50% of all purchases were going to charity during that month.
The total amount to be donated totalled up to a whopping 1,550 USD!
All of which will be donated to the norwegian charity “brystkreftforeningen”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“brystkreftforeningen”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try saying that three times, or even just once… yeah…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charity Link (Page is in norwegian);
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://brystkreftforeningen.no/fa-hjelp/sok-stotte&quot;&gt;https://brystkreftforeningen.no/fa-hjelp/sok-stotte&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;angular-rewrite&quot;&gt;Angular Rewrite&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody knows that Pendoria’s client side code is filled with bugs and lag infested code left over from Pendoria’s initial launch just under 2 years ago.
As a result Xortorx has decided it is time to clean up said code and ensure it runs both smoother and faster.
As Xotrox mentioned in the latest news post that his current goal is to rewrite all of the current client side code inside &lt;a href=&quot;https://angular.io&quot;&gt;Angular 8+&lt;/a&gt;.
While this doesn’t mean anything much to regular players, it will mean less bugs, less lag, and and an overall better experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLDR&lt;/strong&gt;; Less bugs and better performance in the future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-content&quot;&gt;But… Content?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Xortox stated in the news post I mentioned earlier,
due to the development team focusing mostly on the rewrite I doubt anyone will be able to promise any new content any time soon.
Once we feel fairly comfortable with the rewrite he’ll most likely evaluate the possibility of working on some new content on the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content that was already on the ToDo list is still there, it just got knocked behind the rewrite.
On the upside we should be seeing less development bumps in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side Note&lt;/strong&gt;: I’ve been promoted to developer - so I guess that means I’m a little biased now…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;maria-stepped-down&quot;&gt;Maria Stepped Down&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation with Maria is no longer as foggy as it once was,
from the looks of it Maria now has no place in the staff team whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s been a rough past month I have to say I do wish her well in her next project - whatever it may be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rolls-are-not-content&quot;&gt;Rolls Are Not Content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing as Aylea feels the need to “throw some shade” (she calls it this for some weird unknown reason) on me every time she posts on the r/PBBG subreddit,
I felt it would be fitting to address that right here on my post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rolls 👏 are 👏 not 👏 content.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Let me repeat myself.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rolls 👏 are 👏 not 👏 content.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Response; I’m sorry you feel the need to complain about free bound rhodium being given away by staff,
I’ll be sure to let the proper staff members know that this is an issue that really needs to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;/s if it wasn’t obvious :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh god - Aylea makes up 1/4th of my topics this post…. yikes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side Note&lt;/strong&gt;; We have 2 new moderators, so check out &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/join games&lt;/code&gt; and try and win some free rhodium!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;impulsive-updates&quot;&gt;Impulsive Updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to give my blog a much needed overhaul,
it now possesses a cool new theme as well as some cool new features!
Check it out and tell me what you all think - I love constructive criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That actually goes for the content within my posts such as this,
if you see something that could be improved please do let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check It Out!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&quot;&gt;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog gets my latest posts before I convert them to Reddit posts, all of which are about Pendoria.
I’ve been working with some players to attempt to maybe get some other writers to post updates on the other games such as Ava, IQ, or Lyr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-it&quot;&gt;That’s It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, that’s it for this post.
I’m going to continue to write up more, so if you enjoyed it then be sure to read the next one!
If you disliked it tell then me why down in the comments and I’ll consider your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series of posts is archived at the link below if you missed any.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&quot;&gt;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-pendoria-if-you-havent&quot;&gt;Join Pendoria If You Haven’t!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t joined it’s never too late to start playing!
Below I have a referral link that helps me out on the game if you click it and sign up,
so please click that link, however if you don’t want to you can always click the other link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t care, click the first one, it doesn’t hurt you at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please Click Me; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pendoria.net/?ref=334&quot;&gt;https://pendoria.net/?ref=334&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Make Me Sad; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pendoria.net/&quot;&gt;https://pendoria.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Puls3</name></author><category term="Pendoria" /><summary type="html">1.5 Grand For Charity!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pendoria Update Summary</title><link href="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/update-summary/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pendoria Update Summary" /><published>2019-10-08T02:35:11-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-08T02:35:11-04:00</updated><id>https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/update-summary</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/update-summary/">&lt;p&gt;Considering there have been people wondering about Pendoria’s latest updates, I figured I would write up a quick summary about what’s going on in the world of Pendoria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unlimited-modifiers&quot;&gt;Unlimited Modifiers!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously we had double and triple, now after 26h of triple it becomes quadruple, after 28h of quadruple it becomes quintuple, etc.
This can continue for as long as the Pendoria community can push it - we now have higher modifiers than all the other games, because ours are unlimited! This does not effect the stat boost or double drop global modifiers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit: Turns out it maxes at 20, but I think that might only be due to the fact that Maria doubts we’ll ever get there, though I could be wrong about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another Edit: I received a message from Maria later after posting this, I wanted to include it as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s client side, it stops at 20 as I have simply input the name of the multipliers all the way up to x20.
The server could handle it endlessly if the client had the names for it.
Theoretically you could fix that yourself if you really wanted too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Maria &lt;em&gt;(slightly modified)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out it truly is endless!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;modifiers-effect-global-drops&quot;&gt;Modifiers Effect Global Drops!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this patch, modifiers (eg. double &amp;amp; triple) will now effect the amount found from global drops!
For example if you were to find 1 rhodium during double, you would receive 2 rhodium.
This can work alongside the double drop modifier as that only doubles the chances of finding global drops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit: I just got a confirmation from Maria that the global modifiers (eg. double and triple) only effect found Rhodium and Spare Parts, nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shorter-invasions&quot;&gt;Shorter Invasions!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Damage done per wave has been multiplied by a whopping 400! Don’t worry though, now the damage is split between all alive players, this should help prevent a select few from dragging invasions on for hours without lowering the hard cap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;public-task-boost&quot;&gt;Public Task Boost!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people won’t care about this, others will freak out. Previously all guild boosts were publically available both on rankings and on the guild page pardon one; Task Boost. As of this patch it’s getting both a ranking and added to the guild page. It is my estimation that this will make the premier guilds even more competitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pendoria-donating-to-charity&quot;&gt;Pendoria Donating To Charity!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was in my last post, but it was edited in so I wanted to include it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xortrox explained this one really well, so I’ll quote him, but I figured it deserved a mention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the light of breast cancer awareness month we will be donating 50% of all income from rhodium purchases to a breast cancer charity. (link below)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The charity chosen fights for supporting young victims of breast cancer by supplying welfare measures like rehabilitation,
or providing economical support to victims problems with the cost for treatment or medicine. For those interested in everything they do and offer, you can check out this link:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;(Page is in Norwegian) &lt;a href=&quot;https://brystkreftforeningen.no/fa-hjelp/sok-stotte&quot;&gt;https://brystkreftforeningen.no/fa-hjelp/sok-stotte&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Xortrox &lt;em&gt;(slightly modified)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, half of all donations for the entire month of October will be going to the charity, in addition to this an event will be running from October 4th to October 11th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xortrox has stated that he hopes this will have a positive impact for Pendoria’s community,
and that he can continue to do this in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-it&quot;&gt;That’s It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, that’s it for this post.
I’m going to continue to write up more, so if you enjoyed it then be sure to read the next one!
If you disliked it tell then me why down in the comments and I’ll consider your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post was also released on Reddit.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/PBBG/comments/devuu0/pendoria_update_summary/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reddit Version Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series of posts is archived at the link below if you missed any.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&quot;&gt;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-pendoria-if-you-havent&quot;&gt;Join Pendoria If You Haven’t!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t joined it’s never too late to start playing!
Below I have a referral link that helps me out on the game if you click it and sign up,
so please click that link, however if you don’t want to you can always click the other link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t care, click the first one, it doesn’t hurt you at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please Click Me; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pendoria.net/?ref=334&quot;&gt;https://pendoria.net/?ref=334&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Make Me Sad; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pendoria.net/&quot;&gt;https://pendoria.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Puls3</name></author><category term="Pendoria" /><summary type="html">Considering there have been people wondering about Pendoria’s latest updates, I figured I would write up a quick summary about what’s going on in the world of Pendoria.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pendoria’s Recent Changes Explained</title><link href="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/recent-changes-explained/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pendoria's Recent Changes Explained" /><published>2019-09-17T02:55:11-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-17T02:55:11-04:00</updated><id>https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/recent-changes-explained</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/recent-changes-explained/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen a lot of confusion around Pendoria and its latest updates recently, I figured it was time to release an unofficial news post to hopefully lessen both the tension and the confusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pendoria-donating-to-charity&quot;&gt;Pendoria Donating To Charity!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xortrox explained this one really well, so I’ll quote him, but I figured it deserved a mention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the light of breast cancer awareness month we will be donating 50% of all income from rhodium purchases to a breast cancer charity. (link below)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The charity chosen fights for supporting young victims of breast cancer by supplying welfare measures like rehabilitation,
or providing economical support to victims problems with the cost for treatment or medicine. For those interested in everything they do and offer, you can check out this link:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;(Page is in Norwegian) &lt;a href=&quot;https://brystkreftforeningen.no/fa-hjelp/sok-stotte&quot;&gt;https://brystkreftforeningen.no/fa-hjelp/sok-stotte&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Xortrox &lt;em&gt;(slightly modified)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, half of all donations for the entire month of October will be going to the charity, in addition to this an event will be running from October 4th to October 11th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xortrox has stated that he hopes this will have a positive impact for Pendoria’s community,
and that he can continue to do this in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gear-upgrades-are-getting-replaced&quot;&gt;Gear Upgrades Are Getting Replaced&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gear itself will remain the same, however the upgrade feature which added that little +# (eg. +20) to the end is getting replaced with a similar feature.
This replacement upgrade is a personal upgrade tied to accounts as opposed to tied to the gear,
as now you are upgrading your equipment slots as opposed to the equipment itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a period of one month whatever has been upgraded higher will be the one in effect,
the old feature or the new one, after that only the new one will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side Note!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gear upgrades, both before and after have never effected encampment and still don’t.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Karubo’s ROI sheet has been updated for slots; &lt;a href=&quot;http://pendcalc.karubo.de&quot;&gt;http://pendcalc.karubo.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;golden-cogs&quot;&gt;Golden Cogs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Golden Cogs are a new item being added to the game that possess an extremely confusing drop rate (not effected by any drop boosts and starting at 1 every 5,000 actions).
These golden cogs can be exchanged to the server for 5k Spare Parts, therefore setting a base value, as they will be able to be traded via market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Golden Cogs will be required by the new gear slot upgrades feature to upgrade your weapon slot over level 300, which is equivalent to the current gear upgrade level +30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Cog is required per level from 300+, eg. level 301 costs 1, level 302 costs 2, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Maria seemed to leave out, they will be required for all slots, even for TSers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-outskirt-buildings&quot;&gt;New Outskirt Buildings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 new buildings are being added to the guild outskirts, each one of these will add a 1% modifier to all of the guild member’s corresponding encampment stat.
There’s not much to say about this so I won’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;battle-nerfs--ts-xp-changes&quot;&gt;Battle Nerfs &amp;amp; TS XP Changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked about this in my last post, it contains a ton of reasoning, graphs, numbers, and cold hard math.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/dragons-rundown/&quot;&gt;If you’re interested, here it is.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-it&quot;&gt;That’s It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, that’s it for this post.
I’m going to continue to write up more, so if you enjoyed it then be sure to read the next one!
If you disliked it tell then me why down in the comments and I’ll consider your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post was also released on Reddit.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/PBBG/comments/d57cao/pendoria_recent_changes_explained/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reddit Version Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series of posts is archived at the link below if you missed any.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&quot;&gt;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-pendoria-if-you-havent&quot;&gt;Join Pendoria If You Haven’t!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t joined it’s never too late to start playing!
Below I have a referral link that helps me out on the game if you click it and sign up,
so please click that link, however if you don’t want to you can always click the other link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t care, click the first one, it doesn’t hurt you at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please Click Me; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pendoria.net/?ref=334&quot;&gt;https://pendoria.net/?ref=334&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Make Me Sad; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pendoria.net/&quot;&gt;https://pendoria.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Puls3</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve seen a lot of confusion around Pendoria and its latest updates recently, I figured it was time to release an unofficial news post to hopefully lessen both the tension and the confusion.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dragon’s Rundown</title><link href="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/dragons-rundown/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dragon's Rundown" /><published>2019-09-14T12:35:11-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-14T12:35:11-04:00</updated><id>https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/dragons-rundown</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/dragons-rundown/">&lt;p&gt;This is me, Puls3, exporting and reformatting Dragon’s rundown on recent changes to the numbers.
This was a lot of work exporting it from Discord and probably much more from Dragon, so yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to most of this not being my original work I will not be including a referral link in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured having all of this inside a huge quote block would just be annoying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything below here is modified quotes from dragon.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be a bit more transparent around the recent changes here’s a wall of text about the recent ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gathering-xp&quot;&gt;Gathering XP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ends up being a UI change but sets the stage for base boosts soon™.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior, gathering XP per level and required XP per level were something like…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;XP_Per_Level = 1.01^(Level)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;XP_Req_Per_Level = 1.02^(Level) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you leveled up your TS skills you started gaining super high XP per action and needing even higher XP to level.
This created bigger numbers than the server was happy with so we simplified to something like…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;XP_Per_Level = 1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;XP_Req_Per_Level = 1.02^(Level)/1.01^(Level)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, your XP is independent of level and the level XP scales upward per level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This solves 2 issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Server is happy (Yay)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s much easier to add base boosts like shown below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TS Lvl XP: +1 XP per Base Boost Level &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it’s consistent across every level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that this is not me committing anything to roadmap, just making a point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; Gathering XP update makes server happy and creates a better system to add buffs to soon(tm)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enemy-damage-increase&quot;&gt;Enemy Damage Increase&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As some have may have figured out both player HP and enemy damage have an exponential component to them.
The driving reason for the change was that the player HP increased much faster than the Monster damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/dt3rVl9ORU_DI4wUjjI117Fn_vsre6mQL4dg-tEZ8S1VBUENFcA3wNszqPCViqrbGVjEjER-YYWeRmXCtcZyWIVAufKYvJuI4CW3MsvkOL1dUrE1AFDLa-b7cT8Pb3X_G-YHWIiw&quot; alt=&quot;Math Stuffs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outcome is that as players gain levels their progression rate accelerates.
For design purposes we consider this bad because the top players gain a
disproportionate share of the income (and thus resources) and snowball forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; This was a nerf to mitigate snowballing of the highest level players.
Everyone got hit, the higher level you were the more you got hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;critical-hit-damage&quot;&gt;Critical Hit Damage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another buff that was out of line with its compatriots.
If you think about how Critical % Chance (CHC) and Critical % Damage (CHD) relate it’s something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Total Damage = (Damage) * (1+CHC) * (1+CHD) = (Damage) * (1+0.01*CHC_Lvl) * (1+0.1*CHD_Lvl) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you break that out it becomes quite apparent that CHD is significantly more valuable than anything else.
To illustrate that, consider going from level 1000 to 2000 with each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Base: (1 + 0.001 * 1000) * (1 + 0.010 * 1000) = 22

CHC+: (1 + 0.001 * 2000) * (1 + 0.010 * 1000) = 33 (+50%)

CHD+: (1 + 0.010 * 2000) * (1 + 0.001 * 1000) = 42 (+90%)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is non-ideal since CHD and the other SP damage related boosts (CHC, Power, Dexterity)
share the same cost curve as CHD but are less efficient at progressing users.
This update takes CHD from OP OP to just OP. Players with a lot more CHD got impacted the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; CHD was super overpowered, now it’s just overpowered.
I haven’t done the math but my guess is that you should still have CHD as your highest SP boost as a combatant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;base-damage&quot;&gt;Base Damage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This and base armor are complete buffs.
Nothing was removed regarding how they work but new components were added. Prior, base damage gave damage at a lower ratio versus the other (primary) damage components.
At low levels that was fine, but it didn’t interact with the part of the equation that was generating the majority of equations for combatants. To put it in rough terms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Prior_Damage = Power * Weapon_Damage * Stuff + Base Damage`

New_Damage = Power * (Weapon_Damage + Base Damage) * Stuff + Base Damage
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple reasons we went this route:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Base damage no longer sucks. (yay!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prior, if you had a non-ideal weapon you would struggle versus your peers, base damage evens the playing field.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Base damage now scales nicely across all levels and has no real “soft cap”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you double your base damage your damage will see a significant increase (exact % is somewhat dependent on how OP your weapon is or is not)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; Base damage no longer sucks and has ROI as a sink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;base-armor&quot;&gt;Base Armor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base armor was a solid option prior to the enemy damage increase which kind of ruined it.
This was an oops and an oversight on my end.
What we’ve done in the latest release is to add in a factor of % damage reduction granted by it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Prior_Damage_Taken = (Damage) - (Base Armor)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;New_Damage_Taken = (Damage) / (Base Armor * Stuff) - Base Armor&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the above equations really roughly but it now gives an additional small % damage reduction along with the flat reduction you saw prior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/oqONdX_-21l84uCZdUjHbSs4EzYQ-FR2l5qHBmN1_GGHavnXsbgvfq3wtGB4336ew6L92lJZtm6fQDWt0VnkWmOGaPZUSI22uYomIh4SGZ34gk6D443VDpmGLVPRfFGPwF9JzQob&quot; alt=&quot;Math Stuffs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base armor might still be a bit underpowered, but now it’s not useless and in part scales consistently across all levels. This may be worth returning to at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; Base armor used to be good, was terrible after enemy damage got buffed, now is ok&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;out-of-your-league&quot;&gt;Out of your League&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a small change, but basically if you start to snowball super hard and fight level 10,000 enemies as a level 100 player they will be relatively harder than someone who is level 1,000.
Progression is tied in some ways to how much “stronger” the enemies are than you based on your level, this acts as a buffer (not blocker) as folks start to push forward.
I haven’t checked all players but as a general estimation &amp;lt;10% of combatants were affected by this change and anyone under level 7,500 was unaffected (this only kicks in during/after the mid game).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alright, back to being myself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-it&quot;&gt;That’s It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, that’s it for this post.
I’m going to continue to write up more, so if you enjoyed it then be sure to read the next one!
If you disliked it tell then me why down in the comments and I’ll consider your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post was also released on Reddit.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/PBBG/comments/d46o8n/pendoria_dragons_rundown/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reddit Version Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series of posts is archived at the link below if you missed any.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&quot;&gt;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-pendoria-if-you-havent&quot;&gt;Join Pendoria If You Haven’t!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t joined it’s never too late to start playing!
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://pendoria.net/&quot;&gt;https://pendoria.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Puls3</name></author><summary type="html">This is me, Puls3, exporting and reformatting Dragon’s rundown on recent changes to the numbers. This was a lot of work exporting it from Discord and probably much more from Dragon, so yeah.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pendoria’s First Independence Day</title><link href="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/first-independence-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pendoria's First Independence Day" /><published>2019-07-06T05:25:11-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-06T05:25:11-04:00</updated><id>https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/first-independence-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/pendoria/first-independence-day/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;another-news-post-already&quot;&gt;Another News Post Already?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know when you want to wait to do something,
but it becomes even more of a bigger task the longer you wait?
Yeah, that’s this post. Maria has been doing a very good job spamming out helpful updates recently,
and I feared if I waited any longer that this list would get way too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-celebrated-independence-day&quot;&gt;First Celebrated Independence Day?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite my cries last year, Pendoria has never before celebrated The United States’ Independence Day,
recently this has changed as Pendoria celebrates its first every 4th of July event,
equipped with titles such as Free and Independent able to be purchased.
It’s a standard re-skin of the usual events with points as well as loot crates renamed to something more special sounding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is an event a promotion is now active,
all purchases receive 100% more rhodium as well as 1 promotion point per single United States dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The event will continue until July 12th!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;should-i-blame-maria-as-usual&quot;&gt;Should I Blame Maria? (as usual)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the recent Independence Day event Maria apparently had an accidental “typo” in her code,
it resulted in the coveted limited event titles to be incapable of being purchased until almost July 7th.
Chat was unsurprisingly plagued with complaints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blasphemy&quot;&gt;Blasphemy!?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to recent droughts in ingots caused by Lady Luck being less than fair to us Pendorians,
ingots will now have a fixed drop rate! To put this in simple words,
as opposed to an ingot having a one divided by x chance to drop each action,
a single ingot will be provided to you every x actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All drop rate modifiers will still effect the x variable in the same manner and amount as before.
This removes a major dependence on luck from the game,
and everyone seems to be very delighted about it indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-more-market-spam&quot;&gt;No More Market Spam?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Maria referred to as an unintended result of the implementation of buy orders caused quite a stir whenever multiple users flooded the buy order market with pages of multiple buy orders per user,
any Pendoria player knows that on the regular sell order market only 1 order can be put at a time,
the development team has taken a stance on this and completely removed the ability to post multiple buy orders as of July 6th,
no more market spam?
Yes indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;are-annoying-sp-drops-fixed&quot;&gt;Are Annoying SP Drops Fixed?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t necessarily what happened, but it’s the end result that was intended.
So from the first implementation of recent statistics Battlers had gotten both small and large SP drops to show in their log,
recently Maria has made these small SP drops which were previously not shown to TSers,
spam the recent statistics in all of their glory.
TSers obviously didn’t like that, so now we have a filter for recent statistics,
isn’t that nice? Thanks Maria!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;anything-else&quot;&gt;Anything Else?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not all the changes pushed this July 4th, some of the following are a few of the less interesting changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An Encampment tax option has been added so that you don’t run dry of materials.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An Event calendar is now available while and event is running.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tool-tips on what boosts effect Encampment strength.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tool-tips on reminder pop-ups in case you forget what each little thing means.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there you have it, interesting or not, that’s what was modified recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-it&quot;&gt;That’s It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, that’s it for this post.
I’m going to continue to write up more, so if you enjoyed it then be sure to read the next one!
If you disliked it tell then me why down in the comments and I’ll consider your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post was also released on Reddit.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/PBBG/comments/ca0ihc/pendorias_first_independence_day/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reddit Version Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series of posts is archived at the link below if you missed any.
&lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&quot;&gt;https://xpuls3.github.io/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-pendoria-if-you-havent&quot;&gt;Join Pendoria If You Haven’t!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t joined it’s never too late to start playing!
Below I have a referral link that helps me out on the game if you click it and sign up,
so please click that link, however if you don’t want to you can always click the other link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t care, click the first one, it doesn’t hurt you at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please Click Me; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pendoria.net/?ref=334&quot;&gt;https://pendoria.net/?ref=334&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Make Me Sad; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pendoria.net/&quot;&gt;https://pendoria.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Puls3</name></author><summary type="html">Another News Post Already?</summary></entry></feed>